科塔
Kota.
在国内外的教育领域
In the area of education this city has created an identity for itself..
这座城市为自己创造了独特的形象
..nationally as well as internationally.
从一开始，马赫什瓦里教育
And right from the start, Maheshwari classes..
就在这条通往胜利的道路上高举成功的旗帜
..has been carrying the banner of success on this path to victory.
在30年的时间里
Within a span of 30 years
马赫什瓦里教育树立了一个伟大的目标——
Maheshwari classes has embarked upon a mission..
展望整个教育行业
..that envisions the whole world of education..
服务范围从标准八年级教育直至大学
..with services from standard eighth till university.
在这种追求中，马赫什瓦里教育的师资力量
In this pursuit Maheshwari classes has to give credit to its team..
教学方法和以学生为中心的教育理念是至关重要的
..teaching methodology and student-centric approach.
我们非常注重学生的需求
We are now catering to the need of the students..
无论是在学习周期中
..throughout their academic cycle..
还是已经步入职业生涯
..till their step into their professional life.
如此形成一个完整的教育枢纽
The complete educational hub.
千里之行，始于足下
The journey of thousand miles begins with a single step.
从只有一个教室开始，我们一路走来
The credit for having come this far after starting with one classroom..
有请我们的学生
..goes only to our students.
吉安 · 米塔尔
Gyan Mittal.
JEE高考状元，来听听他的看法
All India Rank one JEE Advanced, listen to his own words
我的成功完全归功于马赫什瓦里教育
All the credit for my success goes to Maheshwari classes.
这里是 IIT、JEE考试最好的教练
It is the best coaching for IIT JEE.
每年都有高分学员从这里走出来
Year after year the best results come from here.
在这不仅可以参加 JEE 考试，还可以参加 NEET、奥林匹克、 KVPY、 NTSE 等考试
Not only in JEE, but also in NEET, Olympiad, KVPY, NTSE and other exams.
马赫什瓦里教育，我们将一起做出改变
Maheshwari classes, We will make a change together.
科塔
Kota.
在国内外的教育领域
In the area of education this city has made a name for itself..
这座城市为自己创造了独特的形象
..nationally as well as internationally.
从一开始，马赫什瓦里教育
And right from the start, Maheshwari classes..
就在这条通往胜利的道路上高举成功的旗帜
..has been carrying the banner of success on this path to victory.
在30年的时间里，马赫什瓦里教育树立了一个伟大的目标——
Within a span of 30 years Maheshwari classes has embarked..
您说的我们都清楚，先生
It's not as though we were unaware, sir.
我们甚至在4月份申请了辅导班
We even sought admissions for coaching in April..
但那是在伊塔尔西本地
..but that was in Itarsi. Local.
即便是在那里瓦伊巴夫考的也很好
Vaibhav was doing very well even over there.
他是班上的前三名
He was amongst the top three..
但是到了11月份全国大考的时候
..but when the All India test series took place in November..
我们才开了眼界
..that's when our eyes opened.
先生，瓦伊巴夫的朋友皮尤什是你的学生
Sir, Vaibhav's friend Piyush is your student.
他在学校的成绩落后于瓦伊巴夫，你可以向他确认
He lagged behind Vaibhav in school. You can confirm from him.
可现在就连他也跑在了瓦伊巴夫前面
Even he shot ahead of Vaibhav...
先生，瓦伊巴夫是个非常用功的学生
Sir, Vaibhav is a very hardworking student.
他很刻苦，但伊塔尔西缺乏科塔的教学设施
He even studies a lot but Itarsi lacks the facilities of Kota.
那里只有一个小培训班
Only one small institute exists there.
只有“成功”和“王牌”是小型的，戈埃尔班今年有400名学生
Only 'Success' and 'Ace' are small. Goel-classes has 400 students this year.
是的，我儿子瓦伊巴夫正在上戈埃尔的课
Yes, sir. My Vaibhav was attending Goel classes.
-他是戈埃尔的学生? -是的
He was attending Goel? - Yes.
那他的化学一定很差
Then he must be pretty weak in chemistry.
他不可能跟上我们的进度
He won't be able to cover it alone.
不，先生，我儿子很聪明，他在高中的成绩是90分
No, sir. The boy is smart. He scored 90 percent in high school.
-相信我，他一定能跟上来 -不，他不会
Trust me sir, he will be able to follow. - No. He won't.
超过70万的印度学生在高中能得90分
Pan India more than 7 lakh students score 90 percent in 10th grade.
仅在CBSE（中央中等教育委员会）就有超过20万人
More than 2 lakhs in CBSE alone.
可是印度理工学院有多少座位？
And how many seats do they have in IIT?
只有5273个
5273 only.
如果能得90分就能上印度理工就好了
If only the students with over 90 percent appear for IIT..
即便如此，其中的99%
..even then 99 percent of those
都是考不上的
won't make it.
先生，部长写了这封信您看一下
Sir, the Minister forwarded this letter.
他还打了电话给我
He even called me.
这就是我当面拒绝的原因
That's why I am refusing in person.
我不会给你任何承诺，但这是为你儿子好
Look, I won't make tall promises but it would be beneficial to Vaibhav..
在四月份12年级开学时再来吧
..to join us when the 12th grade batches start in April.
和其他人一起
With all the others.
佛祖保佑
Jai Shree Krishna
你能和皮尤什聊聊吗？
Could you talk to Piyush?
能聊的时候应该都能收到录取通知书了
We should have taken admissions back then only.
你们俩本来可以在一起的
Both of you would have been together.
不管怎样，如果这里不行，也许别的地方可以
Anyways, if not here then maybe somewhere else.
但是现在这里是最好的
But nowadays this is the number one.
你开你车
You better focus on driving
插什么嘴
Smartass.
去塔万迪萨博哪里?  “神童教育”对吧
Where in Talwandi? 'Prodigy?'
你来科塔多久了，兄弟？
How long have you been in Kota, brother?
孩子，我来科塔的时候它还是一个城市，而不是一个工厂
Son, I've been in Kota since the time it used to be a city, not a factory.
当时的培训班没有制服
Back then coaching classes did not have any uniforms..
而且都集中在科塔一个叫做“维根纳加”的小地方
..and this environment was confined to a small locality of 'Vigyan Nagar.
多么恰当的名字! 不是吗，先生？
What an apt name! Ain't it, sir?
是的，阿加瓦尔的一些教育机构曾经就在那里
Yes, some Agarwal classes used to be there.
一些? 阿加瓦尔先生曾经是统治者，先生
Some? There was a time when Mr.Agarwal used to rule, sir.
现在可能有很多的导师，但他是唯一真正的教父
There may be many dons today, but he is the only true Godfather.
科塔工厂就是由他建立的
This Jurassic park was established by him.
他虽然不叫柯里昂，但他是所有人的教父
His name may not be Corleone but he is Godfather to all.
他被称为科塔的斯蒂芬·霍金斯
He is called the Stephen Hawkins of Kota.
不是霍金斯，是霍金
Not Hawkins. Hawking.
哈?-霍金，国王
Huh? - Hawking. King.
对，是的，他是国王
Yes, yes. He is the king.
他自己的孩子可能没能进入印度理工学院
His own children may not have made it to IIT..
但是他让成千上万的孩子进去了
..but he has got thousands of others through.
虽然他不能走路，但他让上万的家庭能够自食其力
Though he couldn't walk by himself but has helped lakhs run their household.
就是因为他，这个城市的每间屋子都有租客
Sir, its because of him every other house in the city has a PG..
然而每个街角都是一团糟
..and a mess at every corner.
而且必须如此
And it has to be.
因为每年有超过20万的学生来到这里
As every year more than 2 lakh students come here.
随便扔一块石头，肯定会砸到学生的
Toss a stone blindly.. ..it's bound to hit a student.
你可别真扔啊
Hey! But don't toss one.
这不是一个城市，而是一个巨大的旅馆
This is not a city, sir. But rather a very big hostel.
在这里，人们关注的并不是哪个培训机构能公布教学大纲
Here the battle is not whether an institute could post the solutions or not
而是哪个机构能够率先做到
But instead, which institute did it first.
这里的每个人都疯了
Everyone here is crazy, sir.
到处都在谈论
Everywhere there is discourse..
哪个机构向高分学生收费的问题
..about which institute charged fees from the topper..
高分学生是从哪个机构出来的
..which institute really educated him..
哪个机构只是买了他的头衔
..and which one simply bought off his rank.
哪个老师被谁挖走了？
Which teacher was poached by whom?
哪个教员辞职自己创业了？
Which faculty quit to start on his own?
反过来又是谁离开了他的教育机构？
And who in turn is quitting his institute?
好好学习吧！
Study a little!
专心开车，兄弟
Focus on your driving, brother.
这里有点像“大老板”
It is a kind of 'Big Boss' running here.
你看“大老板”了吗?-是的
Do you watch Big boss? - Yes, I do.
这里没人看
Nobody watches it here.
这是印度唯一一个
This is the only city in India..
三星打不过诺基亚的城市
..where Nokia dominates Samsung.
如果一定要说的话
If I must add, sir..
来这里的学生可能有些不会被选中
..all the students who come here may not get selected..
但是一个没有被选中的学生
..but a student who doesn't get selected from here..
本就不该被选中
..was never meant to be.
去忙你的吧，我在这等着
Get your work done. I'll wait.
可以的，先生
Yes. It's done, sir.
你确定？
Sure?
绝对没问题
We will get it done, sir.
要有信心，我姐夫开办这个学院时只有一个教室
Be confident. My brother-in-law started this institute with just one room.
你看看现在
And look at it today.
确实很了不起，但是他能跟上进度吗
that's all impressive but will he be able to manage on his own?
怎么会跟不上呢？ 他高中考试得了90分，这可不是开玩笑的
Why not? He scored 90 percent in the boards. That is not a joke.
这孩子很聪明
The boy is sharp .
但是我听说印度理工学院只有5273个座位，所以..
But I heard IIT has only 5273 seats. So..
但是先生，你只需要一个
But sir, you only need one.
瓦伊巴夫
Vaibhav.
他只是想招你进去
Just because he is willing to enroll..
并不意味着你一定要在这补习
..doesn't necessarily mean that you have to accept.
今年最好呆在家里做好准备
Better stay at home and prepare this year..
在12年级的时候直接去马赫什瓦里教育
..and aim for Maheshwari in 12th grade.
爸爸，即使我必须要等12年级才能去马赫什瓦里教育
Dad, even if I have to take admission in Maheshwari for the 12th grade..
那就先让我在这补习吧
..let me study in here only.
我在家里没办法学习
I can't do it at home.
给他登记，把学习资料给他发一份
Enroll him and hand him the material.
-哪一批? -IIT JEE A10
Which batch? - IIT JEE A10.
A10？
A10?
-你们一共有多少批? -只有十批，先生
How many batches do you have in all? - Only ten, sir.
我们没有太多的批次
We don't have too many batches.
少教，教好
Teach less but teach well!!
爸爸，皮尤什告诉我，批次靠后就不会得到什么关注了
Dad, Piyush was telling me that lower batches don't get any attention.
谁说的？
Says who?
-我们没人关注吗? -有的，先生
Do we give attention or not? - We do, sir.
-我在A7 -他在 A7
I myself was in A7. - He was in A7.
先生，收钱可以，但请确批次靠前
Sir, charge the entire fees if you wish but please ensure a better batch.
是这样的，先生，两年的全部费用无论如何都要收的
Look, sir. Entire fees for 2 years will be charged anyways.
但是他的批次暂时改不了
..but he will still be in batch A10.
这是我姐夫的政策
It's brother-in-law's policy.
但批次不是永久性的
But this batch won't be permanent.
改组考试将在两个月后进行
Reshuffling tests will take place after two months..
你考个不错的成绩
..and you will do well in it.
这样批次就提前了
That's it. Batch changed.
这是你的学习资料，制服暂时没有现货
This is your material. Uniforms are not in stock.
后天你就可以拿到了
You will get it by day after tomorrow.
有三所学校可供选择
And you have a choice of three schools. You can enroll yourself in any.
这些学校中哪一所是好学校？
Which of these is a good school?
这有什么关系? 他又不用去
How does it matter? He doesn't have to attend.
我们与这三家学校都有合作
We have a tie-up with all three.
-好的，我先去把这个收起来 -好的
Okay. I'll go and put this away. - Yes.
你好
Hello.
是的，皮尤什
Yes, Piyush.
是的，你终于有时间给我打电话了
Yes. Finally you found the time to call me.
我是瓦伊巴夫
This is Vaibhav.
是的
Yes.
这是我的科塔号码，存一下吧
This is my Kota number. Save it.
是的，今天
Yes. Today.
不，不在马赫什瓦里，是神童教育
No, not in Maheshwari. Prodigy.
为什么要感谢上帝？
Why thank God?
你疯了吗？
Are you crazy?
他们在马赫什瓦里教了这么多东西，这是件好事
It's a good thing they teach so much at Maheshwari.
是的
Yes.
那个一直让我做租客的女士很好，她非常好
The lady who kept me as PG is nice. She is very nice.
她说我就像她的儿子邦蒂
She told me I'm like her son Bunty.
别管那个了，我们见个面吧
Oh, never mind that. Let's meet.
开课之后我就不能来维根纳加了
Once studies begin I won't be able to come to Vigyan Nagar.
要我过去吗？
Shall I come?
哦，我明白了
Oh, I see.
那就明天？
Tomorrow then?
好的，如果你明天没有额外的课就告诉我，我们见个面
Ok. Let me know if you don't have extra classes tomorrow. Will meet.
喂？
Hello?
我可以进来吗？
May I come in?
我是米娜，神童，A5
I am Meena. Prodigy. A5.
你看到楼下的储藏室了吗?-看到了
You've seen the storeroom downstairs? - Yes.
那是我的房间-知道了
That's my room. - I see.
你离开时是不是没关净水机？
You left the RO turned on downstairs. What..?
是的，没有水
Yes. There was no water,
所以我想我忘记关了，对不起
so I guess I left it turned on. Sorry.
用完后把插头拔掉，否则阿姨会很不高兴的
Remove the plug after you use it. Else aunty gets very upset.
哦！
Oh!
阿姨很严格吗？
Is aunty very strict?
今天早上她对我说话还挺客气的
She spoke to me very sweetly this morning.
她在家长面前当然表现很和蔼了
She is bound to speak nicely in front of parents.
家长离开后才是她的真面目
She should have the guts to speak nicely once they've left. Right?
我有一个双向插座，你也可以用
I have a two way socket. You can have it.
插座，为什么？
Socket. Why?
当你的室友来的时候，你们一定每天晚上都会打架
When your roommate comes he will fight every night..
手机充电只有一个插头
..for phone charging. There is only one plug.
不，我一个人住这里
No, I will stay here by myself.
一个人？
All alone?
是啊
Ya.
房租会很贵
The rent will be quite a bit.
如果你有资源，为什么不去马赫什瓦里？
Why didn't you go to Maheshwari if you have the resources?
在马赫什瓦里要得到入学许可并不容易
It is not so easy to get admission in Maheshwari.
是吗? 我被录取了
Isn't it? I got admitted.
在马赫什瓦里?-是的
In Maheshwari? - Yes.
那为什么..
Then why...
这里的学费要低得多，而且他们还用印地语教学
The fee here is far lower and also they teach in Hindi.
另外，吉图·拜亚也在这里
Also, Jeetu Bhaiya is here.
吉图·拜亚？
Jeetu Bhaiya?
你怎么会不知道吉图·拜亚？
How come you don't know Jeetu Bhaiya?
你是从哪条路来的? 他的广告牌到处都是
By which route did you come? His hoardings are all over the place.
他是科塔最好的物理老师
He is the best teacher of physics in Kota..
在非学术界排名第三
..and number three at Unacademy.
非学术界？
Unacademy?
'非学术界'是印度最大的教育类'猩猩'
It is India's biggest education ape.
猩猩？
Ape?
你都不知道'猩猩'? 那你还上什么印度理工学院？
You don't know ape? Then how will you make it through to IIT?
你应该知道手机里面的一个个小方块……
You know the tiny boxes in mobiles. If you send something..
应用程序
Oh! App.
是的，埃普吉图 · 巴伊亚已经上传了 JEE 的整个教学大纲
Yes. Ape. Jeetu Bhaiya has uploaded the entire syllabus of JEE on it.
你可以随时学习，甚至老师也可以从中学习
You can study anytime you wish. Even teachers learn from it.
坦率地说，吉图·拜亚就是没有参加竞选
Frankly, just that Jeetu Bhaiya isn't contesting the elections..
否则他一定是最好的候选人
..else he would have been the best candidate.
你是吉图·拜亚的粉丝?-当然
So you are Jeetu Bhaiya's fan? - Absolutely.
那个人值得粉丝拥护
That man is deserving of fans.
他一刻不停地解答有关国际物理学的论文
He solves papers on International physics to the clock.
印度所有顶尖的物理老师
All the best physics teachers in India..
都把他们的问题汇总起来找他解答
..send their problem books to him to review.
他的工资是10的7次方以上
His salary is more than 10 to the power of 7.
然而，他很开朗、和蔼并且平易近人
Yet he is cheerful, affable and light-hearted.
等等，净水机没有水
Just a minute. Just a minute. Water did not come out of the RO.
那你是怎么喝的水？
Then how did you drink?
这是乌代的房间
This is Uday's room.
他来自乌代布尔，但他告诉阿姨他来自巴特那
He is from Udaipur but he told aunty he is from Patna.
为什么？
Why?
我不知道
That I don't know.
你没问吗？
Didn't you ask?
我为什么要问这个？考试又不考
Why would I ask! It's not a syllabus question.
"一个人陈述，另一个人点头，大师说两个人都是聪明人"
'One said and the other agreed. Nanak says both are wise.'
冰箱里的东西都可以随便吃
Feel free to keep fruits, veggies, yogurt, water, anything in it.
这是个公共冰箱
He has made it a public fridge.
乌代不在这儿吗？
Isn't Uday over here?
他大部分时间住在拉克西米，和西万吉阿姨在一起
He mostly stays at Laxmi PG, with lady Shivangi.
西阿姨非常棒
Very nice lady.
她是乌代的朋友，但跟我更有感情
She's Uday's friend but has more affection for me.
乌代整天在她那学习
Uday studies with her all day long.
他很能学习，甚至都不来上课
He studies so much he doesn't even attend classes.
我也想达到那种境界
I too want to study that much.
米娜
Meena.
你刚在里面？
You were inside?
别叫女士，我是女孩
Call your mother a lady. I am a girl.
- 嗨-嗨我是..
Hi. - Hi. I'm...
瓦伊巴夫，来自伊塔西，神童教育
Vaibhav. From Itarsi. Joined Prodigy.
你和房东阿姨的儿子很像，对吧？
You are like a son to aunty, right?
从走廊传来的声音在这里可以听到
Voices from the corridor are audible here.
连楼下的声音都听得见
Even the sounds from here are audible downstairs.
我是施万吉，乌代的女朋友，但是我告诉阿姨我是他的表妹
I am Shivangi. Uday's girlfriend but have told aunty that I am his cousin.
冰箱可能是公共的，但我不是
The fridge may be public, I'm not.
所以你可以来着打水
So do come, fetch water and leave.
但没有必要闲聊
There is no need for small talk..
除非你有物理和化学的问题
..unless you have doubts in physics and chemistry.
但是只有在米娜解决不了的时候才可以问我
And that too only if Meena is unable to clear it.
解题标准价是半小时两块泡芙
Doubt solving expert. The standard rate is two puffs for 30 minutes..
一小时三块
..and three puffs for one hour.
只有物理和化学吗? 你的数学一定很差
Only physics and chemistry? You must be weak in math.
我的数学最好，生物最差
I was strongest in math. It's bio that I was weak in..
但是我要学医，因为我爸爸是印度理工学院毕业的
..but I am doing medical because dad is an IITian.
你爸爸是印度理工毕业的啊? 哇塞！
Your dad is an IITian? Even dads are IITians?
太棒了！
That's great!
他想让你进入医学界
And he wants you to get into medicine.
这个家庭应该有多样性
There should be variety in the family.
一定是这样的
Correct.
-考虑真周全-周全个屁
IITian thinks correctly. - Variety my foot!
爸爸是理工学院的，所以他了解那里
Dad is an IITian, that's why he knows the truth about IIT.
他不能把他唯一的女儿送到那些贪婪的工程师中去
He can't send his only daughter amidst the lusting engineers..
充满了雄性激素
..who are brimming with testosterone.
他不能接受
He won't be able to endure the meiosis.
我穿了你的短裤，我的还在洗，没关系吧
I wore your bermudas. I hope it is okay. My clothes are in the wash.
没关系，我以后也穿你的
It is okay. I shall wear yours someday.
行，你穿正合适
Actually, they will suit you.
食堂7:30开餐，早点去
The mess starts at 7:30. Go early to eat..
去晚了就没有奶酪了，而且咖喱里只剩下菠菜
..else cheese will be gone leaving only spinach in the curry.
我们一起去吧
Let's go together.
不，我在禁食我得早点睡觉
No, no. I am fasting. I have to sleep early.
我早上6点有课
I have classes at 6 AM.
我早上吃炸甜面圈
I'll have Poha n Jalebi early morning.
上课？
Class?
这么早？
So early?
但是我的时间表是……
But my time-table..
杰图老师跑得比时间表快
Jeetu Bhaiya runs faster than the time-table.
你会知道的
You will have it too.
你在哪个批次？-A10
Which batch were you alloted? - A10.
你接受了? A10
And you accepted it? A10.
是的，迪帕克先生说没问题
Yes. Deepak sir said it won't be a problem.
为什么？
Why?
为什么? A10怎么了？
Why? What's wrong with A10?
怎么了? 先生，且不说JEE考试
Wrong? Sir, leave aside JEE advance..
他们甚至没有准备好普通考试
..they don't even prepare one well for MAINS exams.
毫无疑问没有任何额外课程，没有分期付款计划
No extra classes. No doubt session. No DPP.
时间也会被浪费
Also time gets wasted.
这都是谁告诉你的？
Who provided you all these insights?
听着，你来得已经很晚了，我们破例录取了你
Look, you came very late as it is. We admitted you.
现在你觉得批次有问题，想改批次
Now you feel the batch is wrong. Change the batch.
不是你想怎样就怎样的，孩子，这是你的第一天，积极一点
It's not what you think. It's your first day. Be positive.
快去学习吧，批次都一样的
Just start studying. The batch makes no difference.
先生，如果批次没有区别的话就把我调到别的批次
Sir, if it makes no difference then transfer me.
任何批次都行
To any other batch.
先生，如果我就是A10的水平
And sir, if I am worthy of A10..
那我就待到改组
..then I shall end up there after the reshuffling.
不不不，绝对不可能
No. No. Not possible.
这是我们这的规矩，我们不会给予神童的学生任何特殊待遇
It's a rule. We don't give special treatment to anyone in Prodigy classes.
无论是学生还是老师
Be it a student or faculty.
但是，先生，A10...-杰图先生！
But, sir, A10.. - Jeetu sir.
你好，先生
How are you, sir?
你好吗?-很好，很好，请坐
How are you? - Good. Good, sir. Please sit.
姐夫昨天很想你
Brother-in-law was missing you yesterday.
杰图最近都没来
Jeetu never comes over.
他还打电话给你
He even called you.
姐姐准备了烤鹰嘴豆绒
Sister prepared baked chickpea fluffs.
这正是我没去的原因
That's precisely why I didn't come over.
你姐做饭真难吃
Your sister is a very bad cook
直说还很尴尬
Moreover it's awkward to tell her.
真的，迪帕克
This is absolute truth, Deepak.
这确实是事实
This indeed is true.
去上你的课，孩子
You go to your class, son.
这是物理的入学试卷
This is the entrance test paper for the physics faculty.
你要的
You asked for it.
太好了，先生! 太好了! 这纸也很好，先生
That's wonderful, sir! Wonderful! The paper is very good, sir.
那就赶紧把我的加班费付一下
Then clear my payment, sir.
加班费?-我上个月上了很多额外的课
Payment? - I took so many extra classes last month.
我给你发信息了
I messaged you.
还没付吗?我们马上安排
Hasn't it been cleared as yet? Will get it cleared, sir.
那是你的事，如果我周五之前拿不到钱
Yes, it's up to you. If I don't get paid by Friday..
我就关机走人
..I'll just switch off the phone and leave.
先生
Sir..
有58个国家提供落地签证
There are 58 countries that offer visa on arrival.
我随便去一个
I could be in any of them Then keep looking for me.
带我一起去吧，先生
Take me along if you go, sir.
如果你走了，我姐夫一定会杀了我的
If you leave because of me, brother-in-law will kill me anyways.
你姐夫才不会让你走
Brother-in-law won't let you leave.
他还想办神童国际学校
He still wants to start up Prodigy International school..
工程学院和大学
..Engineering college and Universities.
他需要你来剥削打工人的工资呢
And he will need someone over there who can cut people's salaries.
先生-给你姐夫带好
Sir. - Say hello.
- 是的-长官
Yes. - Sir.
-先生，我需要和你谈谈-什么事？
Yes. - Sir, I need to talk to you.
-你捣什么乱?-没事
Why are you troubling sir? Sir, it's nothing.
等一下，迪帕克
Just a second, Deepak.
老师，我叫瓦伊巴夫 · 潘迪
Sir, my name is Vaibhav Pandey.
我昨天报名参加了十一年级
I enrolled in the 11th grade batch yesterday.
他来的晚，现在他想升批次
Sir, he is a late admission. Now he wants to upgrade his batch.
等等，老师，他都没让我说完
No, sir. He won't let me tell you the whole story.
听着，瓦伊巴夫·潘迪?-是的，先生
Listen. Vaibhav Pandey? - Yes, sir.
你喜欢求人吗？
Do you enjoy begging?
首先，别再求我了
First of all. Stop begging.
如果你想要达到某个目标，那就努力去实现
If you want something work hard and snatch it.
你现在就是A10了，接受吧
The batch you have now is your truth.
两个月后会进行一次测试
A test will take place in two months.
努力一下，你的批次就上来了
Make an effort and you will improve.
但是其他人都经历了入学考试
But all the others got batches through entrance exam.
我连入学考试都没有
I didn't even get to take that That is also a truth.
老师，我绝对不是A10的水平
Sir, I definitely deserve a better batch than this.
为什么要等两个月? 现在就给我做个测试都可以
Why later? Give me a test now. I am willing to sit for it.
您随便问
Ask me questions, sir.
好吧
Okay.
这有五十道题，明天之前答完
Here are fifty questions. You've until tomorrow. Solve these.
你的批次就根据这次成绩来定
The batch you earn after this will be final.
怎么了？
What happened?
你为什么要插手这件事，老师？
Why are you getting involved in this matter, sir?
-你自己的时间都会被浪费掉-谢谢你，先生
Even your time will be wasted. - Thank you, sir.
现在有一个先例了，其他孩子也会要求同样的待遇
Now seeing him other kids will also demand the same.
你要给多少孩子特殊待遇？
How many kids will you test?
又不是每个孩子都来找我，只有他提出来了
Not everybody demands. Only he did.
我们走着瞧，别忘了我的钱
We shall see. Don't forget the payment.
好的，没问题
Yes. Your payment will..
这题太难了
I'm not getting this, buddy.
吃完泡芙之后，你才说你不会？
After finishing the puffs you say you aren't getting it.
之前看题的时候感觉我会做
Seeing the figure I felt I will be able to do it.
这是啥题啊？
What kind of a question is this?
一个人向泡泡机中吹气，要有多少气才能吹出稳定的气泡?
How hard does one blow into the bubble maker to make a stable bubble?
这题老师从来没教过
This hasn't been taught.
你真不会吗，兄弟？
You really can't do it, bro?
天啊！
God!
皮尤什也不接我电话
Even Piyush isn't answering my call.
我该怎么办? 我被困住了
What should I do? I am trapped.
施万吉也走了
Shivangi too has gone.
你都没有学过力学，为什么还要接这套题呢
Why did you agree to this paper when you hadn't studied mechanics?
我当时必须要有点魄力才行
I had to be heroic over there.
四个小时我连三道题都没解出来
I can't solve three questions in four hours.
而且如果就此放弃又很丢脸
And I will be humiliated if I take this with me.
我们走吧
Let's go then.
去哪里？
Where?
我吃了你的泡芙，就要解决你的问题
I had the puffs. So the questions will be solved..
不管是我解决还是别人解决
..whether I solve them or someone else does.
来吧
Come.
我还要准备我自己的考试，没有多少时间
I have to prepare for my own Board exams and I have little time.
-你在学什么?-重组
What are you studying for? - Reshuffling.
- 你还有两个月的时间呢！-没错
You still have two months to go. - Exactly.
这怎么可能两个月就学完
How will this get done so soon?
我也是11年级的学生，还没有学过这些
I too am in 11th grade. We haven't been taught all of this as yet.
你可以问我之前学过的东西
You can ask me anything from before this.
我们11年级的时候学过，但是我都已经忘了
They taught us in the 11th grade. But I've forgotten everything.
你可以问我在这之后学的东西
You can ask me anything that comes after that.
“没有悲伤，没有大麻，也没有朗姆酒”
"No sorrow, no cannabis or your rum."
“我的世界充满了朋友”
"My world is made up of friends."
第一题选b，第二个题选a，第三个题选c
The first is B. The second is A. The third is C.
这么快，兄弟? 请把答案也写下来，多谢
So soon, brother? Please write the solution as well, brother. Please.
你说这是杰图老师出的题？
You said Jeetu sir set the paper. - Yes.
这太简单了，别浪费我的时间
This is too easy. Don't waste my time.
我告诉过你，不是吗? A1的学生非常自私
I told you, didn't I? Students of A1 are very selfish.
这太简单了？
This is too easy?
“没有悲伤，没有大麻，也没有朗姆酒”
"No sorrow, no cannabis or your rum."
“我的世界是由朋友组成的”
"My world is made up of friends."
“我以前在书上读到过，现在写在墙上了”
"I had read it in books. Now it is written on the walls."
“我的世界是由朋友组成的”
"My world is made up of friends."
当然，兄弟，让我看看，你想让我解决哪个问题？
Sure, bro. Show me. Which question do you want me to solve?
给我看看问题，别给我看选项
Just show me the questions. Not the options.
解决每个问题
It's just that every question has a journey..
都是一场没有地图的旅行
..which we have to take ourselves without a map.
兄弟，请解第三题
Brother, solve the third one.
我浪费了两年时间来帮别人解题
I wasted two years to do this.
我不会在最后一年还犯同样的错误
I won't make the mistake in the drop year.
我们只需要问一道题，就十分钟
We are only asking you to solve one question. It will take ten minutes.
如果我花十分钟为别人解答十个问题
If I take ten minutes to solve ten questions for others..
那我就要用一年中的一个月来帮别人解答
..then it will take me one month of the year to clear other's doubts.
对我来说，这就是一个'做'和'死'的选择题，我选择'做'
It's a 'do' or 'die' situation for me. And I want to do 'do'.
走吧，再见
Please leave. Please leave. NOW!!
检查一下，答案是8
Check it. The answer is 8.
但是兄弟，所有的选项都在 θ 和 cos θ 中
But bro all the options are in sin theta and cos theta.
是吗? 那你换道题
Oh, yeah? Show me another question.
是的，这题看起来很熟悉
Yes, this appears familiar.
- 我想我能解决-那来吧兄弟
I think I can solve it. - Then do it, buddy.
我已经连续两天死记硬背了
I've been cramming non-stop for two days.
如果我今天再不和我女朋友聊天，她就会和我分手
If I don't speak to my girl today she'll break up with me.
请理解一下
Please understand.
是吗宝贝，他真是这么说的吗？
Really, bae. Is that what he said?
然后呢？
What happened after that?
明天再来，我明天帮你解决
Come back tomorrow. I'll solve it for you tomorrow.
明天白天来吧
Come during the day tomorrow.
有了！答案是根号3/4，检查一下
Ya! Got it. Root 3/4. Check it.
前三个选项都是图形
The three options are in form of graph.
那第四个选项呢?-以上都不对
And what about the fourth? - None of the above.
那就对了，答案是D
Then that must be it.
就这，你瞅瞅，多简单
You see? I solved it, didn't I?
你被绿了，是吗？
Your girlfriend betrayed you, didn't she?
这种事时有发生
It happens.
没有，我母胎单身
No. I never had a girlfriend.
那一定是你父母要离婚了吧？
Your parents must be getting divorced?
对吧? 不是吗？
Right? No?
-要不你就是同性恋 -哇兄弟，你是同性恋
Or you must be gay. Wow, bro! You are gay.
-我的第一个同性恋朋友 -滚犊子
My first gay friend. - What nonsense are you speaking?
那是什么原因呢？
Then what is the reason?
为什么像你这样一个脆弱无助的男孩
What's the reason that a fragile and helpless boy like you..
会在期中的时候来到科塔？
..left his home, school and all else mid semester to come to Kota?
很显然你不是天才
You are not a genius. That much is obvious.
米娜，他没告诉我们，但是这家伙一定有一段黑暗的过去
Meena, he isn't telling but this guy has a dark past.
乌代！
Uday.
你就不能换个别的时间捉弄人吗
Can't you find a better time for ragging?
我们有一道题解不出来了
We can't solve one question.
如果你能给我们讲讲机械力学，那你就讲一讲
If you can tell us something about mechanics then tell us..
否则麻烦你安静两分钟
..or else remain quiet for two minutes.
我不懂力学，但第三个问题的答案是 c
I don't know about mechanics but the answer to the third one is C.
你这绝对是瞎蒙的
That's plain guesswork.
不是，我看过这个问题
I am not guessing. I have seen this question.
是的，我也很熟悉
Yes, it appears familiar to me as well..
但我已经忘了怎么做了
..but I've forgotten how it is done.
如果有人能给我讲一下就好了
It is okay. If anyone explains a little to me once..
你想再出去问一圈吗？
We got ourselves embarrassed just now. You want to go again?
我以为人们来到科塔就会成为天才
I thought people come to Kota and become geniuses.
淦！
Jackasses!
好主意！
Idea!
同学们，我们今天要解一个比较棘手的题
Kids, we will solve a tricky question today..
如果这道题不使用这个技巧
..and if you don't use the trick in this question..
就会很难解
..it will be difficult for you to solve this question.
如你所见，这里有方块和弹簧
As you can see a block and spring system has been used here.
我以V0速度
Here I have projected the back block..
将后面的方块移到到前面。-就是这个。
..towards the front block with V0 velocity. - This is the one.
弹簧会自动的……
The spring with the natural ability.
往前一点
Go a little forward. A little forward. A little forward.
现在你必须用质心来解这个问题
Now you have to solve this with center of mass.
如果你用质心来解这个问题...-是的，这就是答案了
If you solve this with center of mass.. - Yes, this is the answer.
我们被题干的描述干扰了
We were fooled by the change of language of the question.
当我们必须取质心时，我们用了地面作为参考系
We took the frame of reference of ground when we had to take center of mass.
你看看，米娜，我可不像你，你忘了
You see, Meena. I'm not like you. You forget.
我的讲座可以随时观看
My lectures can be revised anywhere and at any time.
嗯，对
Yes. Alright.
什么？
What?
如果有一个题是雷斯尼克 · 哈利迪出的
If one problem is from Resnick Halliday..
那其他的题可能也都是来自某一本书
..then all the others too can be from some book or the other.
不要仔细读，先留意图形
Don't start reading the text. Look out for the figure first.
如果你找到了对应的，那就读一下问题，这样可以节省时间
If you find the figure, then read the question. It will save time.
我找到那个气泡了！
I found the bubble one!
表面张力等于. .-以后再读，先抄下来
Surface tension equated with.. - Read it later. Just copy it now.
再拿些书来
Bring more books.
这叫什么事啊
These are bad times.
我们还得偷偷溜出去学习
We have to sneak out for studies.
求上帝把我们从印度理工拯救出来吧
God save us from IIT.
“没有朋友的生活有什么意义? ”
"What good is a life with no friends?"
我中枪了救救我 -- 救救我
I've been shot.Help me.. -- Revive me.
杀了他，杀了他
Kill him. Kill him.
他躲在灌木丛里
He's hiding in the bushes.
过来帮帮我
Come help me.
我怎么过去？
How do I come?
快点过来
Please come now.
“我的世界是由朋友组成的”
"My world is made up of friends."
“它由你的爱和你的崇拜组成”
"It is made up of your love and your worship."
“我的世界是由朋友组成的”
"My world is made up of friends."
“我见过几千人，但只有四个好朋友”
"I have met several thousand but I have only four good friends."
“这是每个人的路，这是每个人的呼唤”
"This is everyone's path. This is everyone's calling."
“没有朋友的生活有什么意义? ”
"What good is a life with no friends?"
“别迷路，别走散了”
"Don't get lost. Don't get separated."
“别再迷路了”
"Don't get lost again."
拿去，全都拿去
Take them. Take them all.
我要这书有何用
These books are of no use.
我还想为了她考试印度理工
The one for whom I wanted to crack IIT..
她竟然和一个小贩跑了
..she eloped with a commerce guy.
我们只需要解题
We only need the solution.
这是旧版本啊？
Old edition?
没问题，没问题，没问题
It will do. It will do. It will do.
拜拜，兄弟
Bye. Bye. Bye, bro.
“没有悲伤，没有大麻，也没有朗姆酒”
"No sorrow, no cannabis or your rum."
“我的世界是由朋友组成的”
"My world is made up of friends."
“我以前在书上读到过，现在写在墙上了”
"I had read it in books. Now it is written on the walls."
“我的世界是由朋友组成的”
"My world is made up of friends."
你有钥匙！
YOU have the keys!!
太棒了
Oh yeah!!
“我以前在书上读到过，现在写在墙上了”
"I had read it in books. Now it is written on the walls."
“我的世界是由朋友组成的”
"My world is made up of friends."
够了
Enough already.
解出这么多一定不是A10批了
You will surely get a better batch than A10 with this much.
这都是抄来的的，让我自己解几个
This is copied. Let me solve a few myself.
嘿，兄弟，别告诉杰图老师这些都是你抄的
Hey, bro. Don't tell Jeetu Bhaiya that you copied all these.
仅仅为了几个问题
You will waste the whole night's efforts..
这一晚的努力就全白费了
..just for a couple of questions.
我要去睡觉了
I am going to bed now.
你还要不睡吗？
How much longer will you remain awake?
差不多了，再让我看一会
It's almost done. Only a little longer.
- 祝你好运-好的兄弟，谢谢了
Good luck. - Yes, bro. Thank you.
- 再见-好
Bye. - Yes.
这些都是你做的？
You did all of these?
是的，先生，我花了一整晚
Yes, sir. It took me all night.
你是怎么解的？
How did you do this one?
第三题
The third one?
我们不用地面，而是用质心作为参考系
Sir, Instead of ground we had to use center of mass as the frame of reference.
然后答案就出来了
Then it got done.
正确
Correct.
这个题呢？
This one?
先生，这道题的第一部分很简单
Sir, the first part in this one was very easy.
第二部分改变了惯性运动
In the second part the movement of inertia was changed.
然后就有答案了
Then it got done.
这个？
This one?
在这个过程中要把空气吹成气泡，然后表面张力
In this one had to blow air into a bubble. Then the surface tension..
你一定加倍了-加倍了，是的，老师
You must have doubled it. - Doubled. Yes, sir.
那你一定把它等同了-是的，先生
Then you must have equated it. - Yes, sir.
正确
It's correct.
你的方法是正确的-谢谢老师
Your method is correct. - Thank you, sir.
但答案是错误的
But the answer is wrong.
典型的计算错误
Classic calculation mistake.
无独有偶，沙玛先生的解题方法中也犯了同样的错误
Coincidentally Sharma sir's solution has the same mistake.
最后一版，第98页，第17题
In the last edition. Page number 98, problem number 17.
我给他发了邮件，他会在下一版中更正的
I mailed him. He will correct it in the next edition.
你知道为什么剩下的8道题你解不出来吗？
Do you know why you couldn't solve the remaining 8 questions?
因为这8道题是我设计的
Because those 8 questions were framed by me.
其他问题的答案都在这本或那本书里
The solutions for the other questions are in one book or another.
那些你已经解决的问题
Those you have solved.
你不可能一个晚上就做到这种程度
You couldn't complete these by yourself in one night.
谁和你一起做的？
Who was with you?
谁和你一起？
我最后一次问你，这些题都是你解出来的吗？
I'm asking you for the last time. Did you solve these?
不是的
No, sir.
我只解出了基础题
I had only solved NCERT so far.
昨天的勇气呢？
Didn't you know this yesterday?
昨天你的行为就像科吉利瓦（德里首席部长）
Yesterday you were acting like Kejriwal.
给我一个机会吧，我一定会做到的
Give me one opportunity, sir. Give me a chance. I will do it.
结果怎么样？
What happened?
对不起，老师
Sorry, sir.
你知道指标、教室、教材
Do you know for whom quota, coaching, material..
. . DPP，床单和现成的计算器这些都是为谁设计的吗？
..DPP, sheets and ready reckoner are designed for?
-给学生-给骗子！
For the students. - For rankers.
不是给我们的，我们只是复印，而我们得到了什么？费用！
It's not for us? We only copy. What do we have? Fees.
校长就靠着你们这些学生
The rankers get facilities from fees charged to students like you..
还有像我这样的老师来赚钱
..and people like me make an earning.
像你这样的人来到科塔
Guys like you come to Kota.
9年级玩口袋妖怪，10年级玩吃鸡
Playing pokemon in 9th grade.. ..and PUBG in 10th grade and
11年级来到科塔
Kota in 11th grade.
为什么? 等沙玛先生问了再说
Why? We will answer when Mr. Sharma asks.
你们正在科塔准备IIT 和 NEET的考试
You are preparing for IIT and NEET in Kota.
它看起来很酷，只是一时的流行
It looks cool. It's a fad.
你看报纸上的广告，还有路边的广告牌
You read the ads in newspapers and see the hoardings..
保证100% 的学生都能考上
..that state 100 percent selection guaranteed.
我们也同样要求100% 的入学保证
We claim the same. 100 percent selection guaranteed.
现在你也看到了，你来到这里根本就没有保证
You see that and you come here. There is no guarantee.
我不是在训斥你，我在给你讲道理，坐下
I am not reprimanding you. I am opening your eyes. Sit.
坐
Sit.
你来到科塔是为了什么？
You came to Kota, didn't you? Why?
来学习
To study, sir.
你也可以在家学啊？科塔有什么不一样的？
You could have studied at home. What will Kota do?
想想，给你时间思考一下
Think. Think. This will take time.
科塔提供了一个环境，因为到处都有学生
Kota provides an environment. Since there are students everywhere..
有竞争和焦点，所以我们应该能考上
..there is competition and focus. So we ought to get selected.
如果你没考上呢？
And what if you don't?
老师，即使没考上也没关系
Sir, even if one is not selected it doesn't matter.
必须要完成12年的学习
One has to study for the 12th grade, sir.
来这里学习没有任何损失，老师
It gets done from here. There is no loss, sir.
有，有损失，这就是人们无法理解的
There is. There is a loss. That's what people don't understand.
2年后你们离开科塔
Children leave Kota in 2 years..
但是科塔这么多年从来没有离开孩子们
..but Kota doesn't leave the children for years.
来到科塔会怎样? 它把你和世界隔离开来
What does Kota do? It isolates you from the world.
那么哪个政府垮台了……
Then it doesn't matter in life which government crashed..
谁和谁结婚了，谁赢得了 IPL
..who got married to whom and who won the IPL.
这些都不再重要了
None of it matters in life.
父母，兄弟姐妹，朋友和亲戚，所有的一切都离你而去
Parents, siblings, friends and relatives. Everything is left behind.
剩下你一个人在这里
And you are left here alone.
还剩下什么? 印度理工，翻来覆去都是印度理工
What is left? IIT. You keep harping about IIT over here.
在你这个年纪，当你如此渴望某样东西的时候
When you desire something so much at your tender age..
只有两种结果
..there are only two outcomes.
考上了，你就平静了，舒服了
If you get in then you have peace. You're chilled.
如果没考上，那就只有嫉妒，仇恨和自我怀疑
And if you don't get in you wind up being jealous, rancour and self-doubt.
人在失去信心之后
One loses confidence, brother.
就会认为自己是世界上最失败的人
Then a person deems himself a bigger loser than the world does.
一旦失去了信心，无论你进入一所多么好的大学
After that no matter how good a college you get into..
你不喜欢，因为它不是印度理工学院
..you don't like it because it is not IIT.
七年！四年毕业，三年工作
Seven years. 4 years of graduation and 3 years of working.
这种创伤需要7年的时间才能痊愈
It takes 7 years to come out of this trauma.
你知道印度对欺诈的惩罚吗？
Do you know the punishment for fraud in India?
最高判7年，正因如此，从今以后，不要再作弊了
7 years. So henceforth stop all this fraud.
这里不是你的学校，得高分就能获得老师的关注
This is not your school where you impress someone to get more marks.
在这里，我和你要齐心协力才能让你考上印度理工
Here you and I have to get together to help you get selected.
靠抄袭和死记硬背，你是不可能考上的
You won't achieve that in this manner. By copying and cramming.
电影里都是骗人的
What they show in the films is wrong.
人们通过死记硬背考上了
People getting selected by cramming.
查图尔考不上印度理工，兰乔才行
It's not the Chaturs who go to IIT. Only Ranchos do.
你看过《三个白痴》对吧？
You have seen 3 Idiots, haven't you?
不要再纠结你的批次了，接受吧
Don't be afraid of the batch. This is your truth. Accept it.
好的，老师
Yes, sir.
啥啥不会
0/10 for knowledge
你一个晚上就把《机械力学》全部复习了一遍，这也是事实
It is also true that you brushed up entire Mechanics in one night.
所以，你肯定是一个斗士学生
So, you are certainly a fighter student.
这正是一个老师想要的
And that is all a teacher wants.
啥啥不会，态度还行，孺子可教，升级A5
0/10 for knowledge, 10/10 for efforts
你来晚了，所以有些落后
You joined late hence you are lagging behind.
但你并不孤单
..but you are not alone.
我们将战斗到最后一刻，打败印度理工
We will fight right up till the last moment and crack IIT.
好吗？
Okay?
回答是或不是
Say yes or no.
是，老师
Yes, sir.
去吧
Go.
把这个交给接待员，她快下班了
Give this to the receptionist. She will leave anytime.
好的，老师
Yes, sir.
老师
Sir.
剩下的8道题应该怎么解？
How do I solve the remaining eight questions?
来吧，还有很多人有同样的问题
Come. The repeater batch has the same topic going on.
来吧
Come on.